Bimalesh Sahoo

User Experience Designer

\\$ +49 157 39689677

https://sahoobimalesh.com

As a skilled creative designer with over 5 years of professional experience, I possess the technical and artistic expertise necessary to develop functional design solutions that meet business requirements. Through collaboration with technology, business, and design teams, I have gained a strong understanding of design systems for mobile, iPad, and web applications. I am an efficient problem solver and adept at working as part of a team to deliver projects on time. I approach each new project with a learning mindset and continually strive to improve my skills and techniques.

Skills

User Research/ Design Thinking Personas/ Wireframing/ Ideation Rapid Prototyping/ Animations Storyboarding/ Affinity Mapping Data Viz/ Interaction Design Empathy Maps/ User Journey Information Architecture/ JIRA Agile Development/ Confluence

Tools

Sketch/ Adobe XD/ Axure RP Figma/ Protopie/ Framer/ Miro Photoshop/ Illutrator/ Zeplin Premiere Pro/ After Effects

Education

Masters of Science

User Experience Design

Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt Ingolstadt, Germany

2021 - 2023

Bachelor of Technology

Electronics & Communication

Sikkim Manipal Inst of Tech Gangtok, India

2012 - 2016

Awards



German UPA UX Challenge 2021

Experience

Siemens Healthineers

Oct 2021 - present

Interaction Designer | Working Student

- Contributed to building user research reports and delivering UX solutions
- Designed user interfaces and created clickable prototypes
- Developed animations and design measurement guides in collaboration with the development team
- Worked on various projects such as Nexaris Angio-CT, Animal CT-Scanner,
 Scan&GO, CT-AIRCC, CTgPCI, SOMATOM

Deutsche Bahn

Sep 2022 - present

UX Designer | Masters Thesis

- Designed a Digital Twin UX solution to detect damages on locomotives using HD
 Images captured through a video gate for the Railway Freight Sector
- Utilized Artificial Intelligence to create a 3D model of the locomotive and identify potential damages
- Replaced the existing manual method of identifying damages in wagons that required analyzing each image individually.

Dassault Systèmes

Oct 2019 - Nov 2020

User Experience Designer

- Designed a new product called "Document Management" for the ENOVIA brand from scratch
- Conducted workshops and analyzed insights to facilitate customers' product vision
- Worked collaboratively with stakeholders, product owners, developers, and other team members to ensure deliverables were met
- Designed UI elements, components, and widgets for digital components in line with the project requirements.

Wipro Limited

July 2016 - Oct 2019

UX Designer

- Began design career working with cross-functional teams
- Worked closely with clients and team members to meet business requirements
- Contributed to the design system by delivering UX components
- Operated in an agile environment to deliver solutions on time
- Designed solutions for various clients including HSBC, National Grid, CitiBank,
 Saudi Aramco, and Johnson & Johnson.